<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Fifty queries, seriously propounded to those that question, or deny infants right to baptism By J.B. an hearty well-wisher to their souls, and to the Churches peace.</title>
            <author>Barret, John, 1631-1713.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1675</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 47 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 17 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A78189</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B907A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R212079</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99897741</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99897741</idno>
            <idno type="VID">170924</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A78189)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 170924)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2524:2)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Fifty queries, seriously propounded to those that question, or deny infants right to baptism By J.B. an hearty well-wisher to their souls, and to the Churches peace.</title>
                  <author>Barret, John, 1631-1713.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[6], 26 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for Nevil Symonds at the Princes Arms, and Jonathan Robinson at the Golden Lyon in St. Paul's Church Yard,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1675.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>J.B. = John Barret.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Infant baptism --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:170924:1"/>
            <p>FIFTY QUERIES, Seriouſly Propounded To thoſe that QUESTION, Or deny Infants Right TO BAPTISM.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>By</hi> J. B. <hi>an hearty well-wiſher to their Souls, and to the Churches Peace.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Nevil Symonds</hi> at the <hi>Princes Arms,</hi> and <hi>Jonathan Robinſon</hi> at the <hi>Golden Lyon</hi> in St. <hi>Paul</hi>'s Church Yard, 1675.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:170924:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:170924:2"/>
            <opener>
               <salute>Men and Brethren:</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>THough many of you are exceeding zealous, and confident in your Way; yet I hope you do not think your ſelves in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fallible, or to be as ſure that you are in the right here, as you are that there is a God, or that the Holy Scriptures of the Old and New Teſtament are the Word of God: Now granting that it is poſſible, you may be under a Miſtake in denying our Childrens Intereſt in the Covenant and Right to Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſm, methinks, it concerns you to enquire and examine again and again, whether you be not indeed miſtaken; ſeeing, if the Truth lieth in the Affirmative, that Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren have ſuch a Right, which you oppoſe, then you muſt needs be found very ungrate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful unto God, in denying ſo much of his Grace and Favour, injurious to our poor Infants, in depriviving them (what in you lieth) of their Birth-right, and of the Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing, and very troubleſome to the Church of Chriſt, in raiſing ſo great a buſle there, and making ſo great a Breach. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I cannot but earneſtly requeſt this of
<pb facs="tcp:170924:3"/>all of you that have any ſeriouſneſs, and tenderneſs of Spirit, that you would not take up your Opinion upon Truſt; but make ſome further Search and enquiry after the Truth. It may be ſafe for you, let it not be grievous to you, to view over theſe Queries: Of which yet I muſt ſay, as the Young Prophet ſaid of the Axe (2 <hi>Kings</hi> 6.5.) They are but borrowed being collected out of a ſeaſonable and uſeful Piece of a Worthy Authour, Entituled, <hi>[more Proofs of Infants Church memberſhip, and conſequent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly of their Right to Baptiſm]</hi> I would hope that theſe Lines will lead and direct you to the Book it ſelf, being as an Index to it. Some of the Queſtions put here I am ſure are ſuch as you ſhould be prepared to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer unto God, and Conſcience; Conſider of theſe things, and the Lord give you Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtanding. <hi>Farewel.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <opener>
               <salute>Reader,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>IF thou wouldeſt have fuller Satisfaction, that it is the undoubled Will of God, that Infants be Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of his Viſible Church, as verily as they are Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of Kingdoms, Cities, and Families, and that they are as capable of it, and that Chriſt was in his
<pb facs="tcp:170924:3"/>Infancy the Chief Member of the Church, even the Head, its Prophet, Prieſt, and King, though yet he did not Teach, Sacrifice, Rule or Intercede actually, and that God never had a Church on Earth ſince there were Infants in the World, of which Infants were not Members, (except any did congregate that had no In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants, or a few ſingular Perſons in the end of the World have upon miſtake refuſed the Priviledge) and that the Goſpel hath clearly acquainted us that Chriſt hath not deprived Infants of this Benefit, but more ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly given and confirmed it; and that he hath inſtituted Baptiſm to be the initiating Sacrament, and Solemn Inveſtiture of Viſible Church-members; And yet that we may hold Loving and Comfortable Communion with thoſe that by unwilling Error do think that Infants ſhould not be baptized, if they will but profeſs that <hi>they heartily conſent that their Children be Chriſt's as far as he will accept them,</hi> and with them that to ſatisfie their doubting or miſtaking Conſciences are re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>baptized, and when they have done will live in Love and Communion with others; And that thoſe few of the Ancients that were for the delaying of the Baptiſm of Infants a while, did not dream of denying or delay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing their Covenant-intereſt and Church-memberſhip according to their Infant Capacity, but only the Baptiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mal Solemnization and Inveſtiture, that it might be more powerfully obligatory: (as Kings are oft crowned long after they are Kings) All this and much more, you may ſee fully proved in the Book from which theſe Que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries are collected, lately Printed, and in the Authors former Treatiſe of Infants Church-memberſhip and Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſm. Theſe Queries more are here further offered to every conſcientious Doubter, Whether it be at all cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dible that thoſe <hi>Jews</hi> that were ſo quarrelſome with
<pb facs="tcp:170924:4"/>Chriſt, and tenacious of their Legal Rights, would ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver have quarrelled with Chriſt or his Apoſtles, for ſhut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting all Infants out of the Viſible Church, if he or they had done it? And whether thoſe Jewiſh Chriſtians that were ſo loath to let go Circumciſion, would have let go even their Infant-Memberſhip and Covenant-right, without one Word of Exception? What conſiderate Perſon can believe this? <hi>2.</hi> Yea when Chriſt offered to gather all <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> and her Children, as a Hen ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thereth her Chickins, and the <hi>Jews</hi> were broken off but by <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nbelief, whether the Children of the Believing <hi>Jews</hi> then were broken off? <hi>3.</hi> And when the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms of the World becomes Chriſt's Kingdoms; are In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants no part of the Kingdoms?</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:170924:4"/>
            <head>Some Sober Queries gathered out of M<hi rend="sup">r.</hi> 
               <hi>Baxters</hi> [more Proofs of Infants Church-Memberſhip, and conſequently their Right to Baptiſm] ſeri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly offered to ſuch as are ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken with the unthankful Er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ror of denying and rejecting of their Infants Rights, and Bleſſings.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> I. <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hether under the Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant of Works,<note place="margin">V. p. 77, 79, 112.</note> if <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dam</hi> had not ſinned, Infants ſhould not have been holy to God, and ſo Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of the Innocent Church or Kingdom of God?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> II.<note place="margin">V. p. 112.</note> Whether God was any more ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liged to order it ſo, that the Children of Righteous Parents ſhould have been born with all the perfections of their Parents, and enjoyed the ſame priviledges, than he was obliged in making the Covenant of Grace to grant that Infants ſhould be
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:170924:5"/>of the ſame Society with their Parents, and have the Immunities of that Society?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> III.<note place="margin">V. ibid.</note> Whether we have any reaſon, when the deſign of Redemption is the mag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifying of Love and Grace, to think that Love and Grace are ſo much leſs under the Goſpel to the Members of Chriſt, than un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Law to the Members or Seed of <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dam,</hi> as that then all the Seed ſhould have partaken of the ſame Bleſſings with their righteous Parents, and now they ſhall all be turned out of the Society whereof the Parents are Members?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> IV.<note place="margin">V. p. 79, 80.</note> Whether though our Innocency be loſt, parents be not parents ſtill, and have not as much Intereſt in children, and whether God have ever reverſed this natu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Order? and if God change not his or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der therein, whether parents be not as capa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble of conſenting to Grace for their child<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ren, as they were of being innocent for them?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> V.<note place="margin">V. p. 81, 83.</note> Whether Infants be not included in the firſt Edition of the Covenant of Grace made with <hi>Adam?</hi> (<hi>Gen.</hi> 3.15.) Whether unleſs it can be proved that In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſants are none of the Womans Seed, we muſt not take that Fundamental promiſe to extend to Infants?<note place="margin">V. p. 96.</note> And was ſhe not there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by obliged to liſt her ſelf, and all her Infant-progeny in the Redeemer's Army, againſt the proclaimed Enemy, and to teach her poſterity to do the like?<note place="margin">V. p. 94.</note> And did they not continue viſible Members of Chriſt's Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:170924:5"/>and Kingdom, till ſuch time as they violated that Fundamental Obligation, and as the Seed of the Serpent fought againſt Chriſt and his Kingdom,<note place="margin">V. p. 95.</note> for Satan and his Kingdom?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> VI.<note place="margin">V. p. 82, 83.</note> Whether in that firſt Proclamati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Grace to fallen man, or in the firſt pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe of Redemption to ſinners, <hi>Gen.</hi> 3.15. An Infant of the Woman be not promiſed to be General, and Head of the Church? And whether the promiſe of an Infant Head, doth not declare God's mind that he will have Infants Members, becauſe the Head is the principal Member? Whether God doth not aſſure us hereby, that he doth not exclude the Infant-ſtate, or Age from the redeemed Church, which he admitted into the Church by the Laws of Creation? Would he have made the Head firſt an In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fant; if he had excluded the Infant-ſtate from the viſible Church? Is not the Head a Member, even the principal Member? And are not Infants hereby clearly warranted to he Members of a lower Nature? If an In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fant may be Soveraign, then may not In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants be Subjects? If an Infant may be the chief Prophet of the Church, then may not Infants be Diſciples? if it be ſaid, they are no Diſciples that learn not; may it not as well be ſaid, he is no Prophet that teacheth not? If it be granted, that Chriſt in Infan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy was the Prophet of his Church by de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignation,<note place="margin">V. p. 86.</note> (though not <hi>in actu exercito?</hi>) Why may not Infants be Diſciples too by
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:170924:6"/>Deſignation, or Separation (though not yet actual Learners?)</p>
            <p>How doth their Infancy incapacitate them to be in Covenant with God,<note place="margin">V. p. 84.</note> to be Church-members, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> when Chriſt in In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fancy bare all the Connter-relations, and was in the Covenant of God as Mediator; and that (as far as we can judge) only by a virtual, and not actual conſent (in his In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fancy and Humane Nature) to the Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant of Mediation?</p>
            <p>If an Infant <hi>qua talis,</hi>
               <note place="margin">V. p. 88.</note> as ſuch be exclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded from Church-memberſhip, then will it not hold <hi>ad omnes</hi> univerſally, and then had not Chriſt himſelf been excluded?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> VII.<note place="margin">V. p. 118, 119.</note> Why are thoſe two Titles put on thoſe two diſtinct Generations, (<hi>ſcil.</hi> the Poſterity of <hi>Cain,</hi> and the Poſterity of <hi>Seth</hi>) calling one the Sons of God, and the others the Daughters of men, <hi>Gen.</hi> 6.2. But that the one was a Generation ſepara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted from the Church from their Birth (their Progenitors being caſt out before them) when the other was the Seed of Saints not caſt out, but Members of the Church, or the Sons of thoſe who were de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voted to God, and ſo devoted to him them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, a ſeparated Generation belonging to God as his viſible Church? Were theſe call<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the Sons of God in regard of their god<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lineſs (who were ſo wicked that God re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pented that he had made them, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroyed them in the Flood) or for their Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation, Church-ſtate, and viſible Separation
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:170924:6"/>from open unchurched Idolaters? like thoſe <hi>Deut.</hi> 14.1, 2.</p>
            <p>Doth it not hence appear that the Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration of the righteous then even from the Womb,<note place="margin">V. p. 119, 120.</note> were numbered among God's peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, in that they are not mentioned as a peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple called out here and there, and initiated at Age? (there is no mention, or hint, of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny ſuch thing) but as a Stock or Generati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on oppoſed to the Daughters of men, or of the unchurched, who were ſuch from their Infancy, as all will grant? were they the ſame men that were Parents of thoſe here called the Daughters of men, and of thoſe called the Sons of God?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> VIII.<note place="margin">V. p. 122.</note> Whether it was not the ſame Church before, and after <hi>Abraham</hi>'s time, that was called the Tents of <hi>Sem? Gen.</hi> 19.27. Was not the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> Church de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nominated the Tents of <hi>Sem?</hi> And does it not hence appear, that the Church-priviledges of that people did not begin with or from <hi>Abraham,</hi> but that they were before? And how was it the ſame Church that was of <hi>Sem,</hi> and of <hi>Abraham,</hi> if it had not the ſame ſort of Members, or materials; if Infants were not Members before <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham</hi>'s dayes, as well as after? And if <hi>Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phet</hi>'s Children muſt dwell in <hi>Sem</hi>'s Tents,<note place="margin">V. p. 123.</note> then will it not follow, that as <hi>Sem</hi>'s In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants were Church-members, ſo <hi>Japhet</hi>'s (or the converted <hi>Gentiles</hi>) Seed are not caſt, or left out?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> IX.<note place="margin">V. p. 7<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</note> Whether if we could ſhew no
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:170924:7"/>written Law or promiſe at firſt conſtituting the Duty, or granting the priviledge of Church-memberſhip, it were the leaſt diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paragement to our Cauſe, as long as we can ſhew thoſe following Laws which preſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe this? If <hi>Moſes</hi> at the end of that 2000 years the Church of God had been without any written Law, found all the Infants of Church-members in poſſeſſion of this bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit; what need was there of a new Law about it? Or why ſhould God promiſe it as a new thing?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> X.<note place="margin">V. p. 115.</note> Whether there being certain proof in Scripture of Infants Church-mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berſhip, but none except that before alledg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed from <hi>Gen.</hi> 3. that makes any mention of the beginning of it, but all ſpeaking of it as no new thing; we have not great rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to aſſign its beginning which from <hi>Gen.</hi> 3. is before ſpoken of?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XI.<note place="margin">V. p. 97, 98.</note> Is it not unqueſtionable, that the Covenant of Grace made to <hi>Abraham</hi> the Father of the faithful, comprehended In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants for Church-members? And was it not the ſame with that <hi>Gen.</hi> 3.15. But in ſome things clearlier opened? Were not both theſe the Covenant of Grace and free Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fication by Faith in the Redeemer? And did not the Covenant made to <hi>Abraham</hi> and his Seed, comprehend Infants? And ſhould not the ſame promiſe expreſſed more con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciſely be expounded by the ſame expreſſed more fully?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XII.<note place="margin">V. p. 115.</note> Whether (though the <hi>Hebrews</hi>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:170924:7"/>had their peculiarities) it be at all credible, that the Infants of that one ſmall Country only ſhould be ſo differently dealt with by God, from all the World elſe, even <hi>Enoch</hi>'s, <hi>Noah</hi>'s, <hi>Sem</hi>'s, and all from <hi>Adam</hi> to the end of the World, that theſe Infants only ſhould be Church-members, and no others?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XIII. What can be more abſurd, than to maintain a Tranſient Fact (as Mr. <hi>T.</hi> hath done) making Infants Church-members, without any Law, Promiſe, or Covenant Grant of God giving them Right? Whether a Gift that was never given be not a contradiction? (<hi>V. p.</hi> 32, 35, 39, 44, 45, 151.) And if there was any ſuch Promiſe, or Covenant-grant of In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants Church-memberſhip, when, or where was it revoked?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XIV.<note place="margin">V. p. 19.</note> Was it only the Infants of the <hi>Hebrews,</hi> or of thoſe that were at their ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolute diſpoſe, that were Church-members? Were not the Infants of free Proſelytes Church-members too?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XV.<note place="margin">V. p. 21.</note> Was it not then the Duty of all the Nations round about, that could have information of the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> Religion, to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gage themſelves, and their children to God by Circumciſion?</p>
            <p>And did not many of the people in <hi>He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter</hi>'s time become <hi>Jews,</hi>
               <note place="margin">V. p. 24.</note> 
               <hi>Heſt.</hi> 8.17. who yet were not under their Government? And is it not well known, that this was to be circumciſed, they and their little ones (as the Proſelytes were) and ſo to keep the Law of <hi>Moſes?</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="8" facs="tcp:170924:8"/>
            <p> And whether the circumciſed Servants of <hi>Iſrael</hi> ſold away to another Nation,<note place="margin">V. p. 145.</note> and ſo ſeparated from the Civil State of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> did <hi>eo nomine</hi> ceaſe to be Church-members, though they forſook not God? And ſo of the Infants, if they were ſold in Infancy? And ſo whether Infants might not be Church-members, that were not of the <hi>Jews</hi> Commonwealth?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XVI.<note place="margin">V. p. 26.</note> Were not the <hi>Iſraelites</hi> Children Members of the univerſal viſible Church, as well as of the Congregation of <hi>Iſrael?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>As he that is a Member of the City is a Member of the Kingdom,<note place="margin">V. p. 146.</note> and a part of a part is a part of the whole; ſo was not every Member of the <hi>Jews</hi> Church alſo a Member of God's Univerſal Church?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XVII.<note place="margin">V. p. 27.</note> Was there ever any true Church, or Eccleſiaſtical worſhipping Soci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ety appointed by God in all the World ſince the Fall, but the Church of Chriſt? Were not Infants therefore either Members of Chriſt's Church, or of no Church of God's Inſtitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion? Was not <hi>Moſes</hi> Chriſt's Uſher, and <hi>Moſes</hi> Church and Chriſt's Church one, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to God's Inſtitution?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XVIII.<note place="margin">V. p. 124, 125.</note> Whether was <hi>Abraham</hi> made a Member of the Church by Circumciſion, or circumciſed becauſe a Member of the Church? The like of Infants born in his Houſe?</p>
            <p>And how can the ceaſing of Circumciſion prove Infants Church-memberſhip ceaſed,<note place="margin">V. p. 127, 128.</note> any more than it can prove their Church-memberſhip
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:170924:8"/>began with Circumciſion; or that Women were not Church-members, becauſe not circumciſed; or that all <hi>Iſrael</hi> was unchurched in the Wilderneſs, when they were uncircumciſed for forty years?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XIX.<note place="margin">V. p. 126,</note> Whether the bleſſing of <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham</hi> conſiſts not chiefly in this, that God promiſed to be a God in Covenant with him, and his Seed? And how are the Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieving <hi>Gentiles</hi> bleſſed with faithful <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham,</hi> and Heirs of the ſame Promiſe, if their Infants are not alſo comprehended in the ſame Covenant?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XX. Whether in that great Promiſe,<note place="margin">V. p. 126, 127.</note> 
               <hi>Gen.</hi> 12.3. Tribes, Kindreds, Families, do not moſt certainly comprehend Infants? As it was to ſuch Families that the promiſe was made before Chriſt, as to the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> Church? What warrant have we to under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand Families or Tribes otherwiſe, when the ſame promiſe is made to the <hi>Gentiles?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XXI. Whether the ſecond Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandment,<note place="margin">V. p. 135.</note> 
               <hi>Exod.</hi> 20.5, 6. doth not con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain a ſtanding promiſe, and diſcovery of God's Reſolution, concerning the children of all that love him, whether <hi>Jews</hi> or <hi>Gentiles,</hi> to whom this Commandment be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs?<note place="margin">V. p. 136.</note> Whether God meaneth not that his Retribution to Parents that love or hate him, ſhall extend to their children as ſuch; unleſs they interrupt it at Age by their own Acts; and if to their children <hi>quà tales,</hi> then whether not to Infants? And when God hath recorded this, decreed, granted,<note place="margin">V. p. 137.</note>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:170924:9"/>diſtinguiſhing mercy to the children of the faithful as ſuch in Tables of Stone, whether it be not a viſible notification, which will make them viſible Favourites and Church-members as ſoon as they viſibly exiſt?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XXII.<note place="margin">V. p. 138.</note> Whether any without the Church are ſecured of God's mercy by pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe? And whether mercy be not promiſed to the Children of the Faithful as ſuch? (See <hi>Pſal.</hi> 102.28. and 103.17. <hi>Prov.</hi> 20.7. <hi>Iſai.</hi> 61.8, 9. and 65.23. <hi>&amp;c.</hi>)</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XXIII.<note place="margin">V. p. 143.</note> Whether theſe Promiſes in the making of them were limited to a cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain time when they were to ceaſe? Or whether they have been ſince revoked?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XXIV.<note place="margin">V. p. 146.</note> If it was on the <hi>Jews</hi> reje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction of Chriſt that they were broken off from being God's people, were thoſe thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſands of <hi>Jews</hi> that believed in Chriſt ſo broken off? If not, then whether were not the Children of all believing <hi>Jews</hi> Church-members in Infancy? Or otherwiſe, was it not ſomewhat elſe than Unbelief that brake them off?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XXV.<note place="margin">V. p. 146, 147.</note> Were not the Infants of the <hi>Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtian Jews</hi> the day before their converſion Members of the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> Church, and of Gods univerſal Church (of which the <hi>Jews</hi> were but a part? and doth it not ſound ſtrangely, that ſuch Infants as were the day before Members of the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> Church, and of God's univerſal Church, ſhould be put out of the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> and the whole viſible Church by the Faith of their Parents, or without Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>belief?
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:170924:9"/>Either it was a mercy to be a Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of the Church, or not: If it was no mercy, then will it not follow, that the unbelieving <hi>Jews</hi> loſt nothing by being broken off? If it was a mercy, how did the <hi>Chriſtians</hi> Children forfeit it?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XXVI.<note place="margin">V. p. 147.</note> Whether it be credible that he who came not to caſt out <hi>Jews,</hi> but to bring in <hi>Gentiles,</hi> breaking down the partition-wall, and making of two one Church, would have a Church of ſo different form and conſtitution, that the Church at <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> ſhould have Infant-members, and the Church at <hi>Rome</hi> ſhould have none? That the <hi>Jews</hi> Infants ſhould be Members, and not <hi>Gentiles?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>If the <hi>Jews</hi> were broken off by unbelief,<note place="margin">V. p. 147.</note> ſhould they not be graffed in again upon their Repentance of Faith? And ſo ſhould not every repenting believing <hi>Jews</hi> Infants be Church-members? Or otherwiſe how would their graffing in anſwer to their breaking off? Should they be but in part graffed in?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Q.</hi> XXVII. Was not Chriſt's Church,<note place="margin">V. p. 148.</note> Spiritual before his Incarnation (when it took in Infants) and gathered in a ſpiritual way? was not the viſible frame of the <hi>Jew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh</hi> Church ſet up and erected by the Father of Spirits, and were not Spiritual Duties commanded then, upon promiſes of Spiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual Bleſſings, even life eternal?</p>
            <p>How will any prove that it was a Blemiſh to the old frame;<note place="margin">V. p. 148.</note> that Infants were Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers?
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:170924:10"/>What was the Church the worſe for Infants Rights? If it be no blemiſh, why muſt it be done away?</p>
            <p>Q. XXVIII.<note place="margin">V, p, 149.</note> In what regard were the new frame better, ſuppoſing the caſting out of Infants, which were in the old? How doth Infants relation detract from its Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rituality? Do not the adult come in by the ſame kind of conſent for themſelves, as they make for their Infants? And do not the Adult blemiſh the Church with more carnal ſins than Infants do? Would any Kingdom be more excellent, if all Infants were disfranchiſed? Does not Nature teach all Kingdoms on Earth to take them for Members, though but Infant-members?</p>
            <p>Q. XXIX.<note place="margin">V. p. 149, 150.</note> Whether any <hi>Jew</hi> at age was a Member of the old Church without pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſing Faith (in the Articles then neceſſary to Salvation) Repentance and Obedience? And wherein the ſuppoſed new call and frame doth in this differ from the old; ſave only that a more full and expreſs Revelati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Chriſt requireth a more full expreſs Faith? Is it not evident, that they were to profeſs conſent to God's Covenant, which whoſo denied <hi>Aſa</hi> would put to death?<note place="margin">v. p. 4<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</note> And was not circumciſion a covenanting Act? And did they not thereby profeſs to take God for their God? Or would God elſe have taken them for his people? And would not renouncing God have cut them off?<note place="margin">V. p. 78.</note>
            </p>
            <p>Q. XXX Whether God's Law obligeth
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:170924:10"/>not perſons to devote themſelves, and their Infants to God, by conſenting to God's Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venant for themſelves and them?<note place="margin">V. p. 50.</note> Whether it was not the Duty of the <hi>Iſraelites</hi> to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gage and devote their children to God in Covenant? Whether this be not evident from the penalty (even to be cut off from his People) annexed for the <hi>non</hi>-perform<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance? (And whether this be not as much our Duty ſtill?)<note place="margin">V. p. 105.</note> Does not the Law of Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture bind us to give to every one his own due? And are not Infants God's own due? Does not the Law of Nature bind Parents to give them up to God, by acknowledging his right, with a free reſignation and dedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation of the Infant to God, as his own; for his uſe and ſervice, when he is capable thereof? If Infants are not capable of do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing (preſent) Service; yet are they not ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pable at preſent of a legal Obligation to fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture Duty, as alſo of the relation following the Obligation?<note place="margin">V. p. 49.</note> And is it not the very na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of our own holy Covenant, that in it we give up to God, our ſelves, and all that is ours according to the capacity of the all? Are not Infants capable of Infant-re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation, Obligation, and Right? What is it that a ſanctified man muſt not devote to God that is his?<note place="margin">V. p. 308.</note> Are we allowed to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept children? Should not Infants there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore be devoted according to their capacity, which God himſelf hath expounded? And if Parents may and muſt devote them pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vately by heart-conſent,<note place="margin">V. p. 106.</note> will it not follow
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:170924:11"/>they muſt do it publickly in the inſtituted way?</p>
            <p>Q. XXXI.<note place="margin">V. p. 198, 199.</note> Whether Anabaptiſts them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, all of them that are truly pious do not vertually (though not actually) devote their children to God, and conſent to their Covenant-relation, while they vehemently plead againſt it?</p>
            <p>Q. XXXII.<note place="margin">V. p. 152.</note> Is it not a deſperate under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taking, and dare any adventure on it, to juſtifie all the World before Chriſt's Incar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation, except the <hi>Jews,</hi> from the guilt of not dedicating their children to God? And do not they that ſay there is no Law in this caſe,<note place="margin">V. p. 153.</note> ſay there is no Tranſgreſſion? And dare any in like manner undertake to juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie at the Bar of God all the World ſince Chriſt's Incarnation from the guilt of ſin, in not dedicating their children to Chriſt, and entring them into his Covenant as Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of his Church? Dare any maintain that all the World is ſinleſs in this reſpect?</p>
            <p>Q. XXXIII.<note place="margin">V. p. 34, 35.</note> Is it not a great Benefit, and Priviledge to be a viſible Church-mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of Chriſt as Head of the Church, and of his Church as viſible? Is it not a benefit in it ſelf (beſides the conſequents) to be vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſibly united and related to Chriſt and his Body? Is not ſuch a Relation to God the Father, Son, and Holy Ghoſt, and to the Church, an honor? And how great is the miſery of the contrary ſtate?</p>
            <p>And if Infant Church-memberſhip were no benefit,<note place="margin">V. p. 33.</note> then how were they that had i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:170924:11"/>(when they came to age, or their Parents in the mean time) obliged to any thankfulneſs for it? Will any ſay, that neither they nor their Parents were obliged to thankfulneſs upon this account?</p>
            <p>Q XXXIV. Is it not certain,<note place="margin">V. p. 111, 112.</note> that In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants are capable of this benefit, if God de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny it not, but will give it them as well as the aged? And is it not certain that they are actually Members of all the Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealths in the World? <hi>(perfectè, ſed imperfe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cta membra)</hi> And does not nature ſeem a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctually to have taught moſt people on Earth, to repute their Infants in the ſame Religi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Society with themſelves, as well as in the ſame civil Society?</p>
            <p>Q. XXXV.<note place="margin">V. p. 113, 114.</note> Whether according to the te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour of the Covenant of Grace, God will not vouchſafe to be their God, and take them for his people, that are (in a natural, or Law-ſence) willing to be his people, and to take him for their God? And whether the Infants of believing Parents are not thus willing? When Infants cannot be actually willing themſelves in a natural ſence, muſt not the reaſon, and will of another be theirs in Law-ſence, that is, of the Parents, who have the full diſpoſe of them, and are war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ranted by the Law of nature to chuſe for them (for their good) till they come to the uſe of reaſon themſelves?</p>
            <p>Whether in God's acceptance the child doth not thus truly conſent by the believing Parents, and doth not covenant with God,<note place="margin">V. p. 286, 287.</note>
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:170924:12"/>as a child covenanteth and conſenteth re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putatively among men, who by his Parents is made a party in a contract, as in a leaſe for his life, or the like?</p>
            <p>And ſo granting the Relation of Church-memberſhip to be founded in a mutual con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tract, covenant,<note place="margin">V. p. 68, 69, 169, 171.</note> or conſent betwixt God and us, yet muſt not this conſent on our part differ according to the different age and ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacity of Infants, and the adult? Were not the <hi>Iſraelites</hi> Infants Church-members, who conſented not actually in their own perſons, but virtually, and reputatively?</p>
            <p>Q. XXXVI.<note place="margin">V. p. 110, 111.</note> Whether it be not the duty of Parents by the Law of nature, to accept of any allowed or offered benefit for their children? The Infant being not <hi>ſui Juris,</hi> but at his Parents diſpoſe in all things that are for his good, have not the Parents power to oblige their children to any future duty or ſuffering, that is certainly for their own good? And ſo may they not enter them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Covenants accordingly? And is it not unnaturally ſinful for a Parent to refuſe to do ſuch a thing, when it is to the great be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit of his own child? And doth it not de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve to be called, the unthankful Error, that oppoſeth childrens Rights, and Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſings? (<hi>V. p.</hi> 339.)</p>
            <p>Q. XXXVII.<note place="margin">V. p. 100.</note> VVhether it may be thought, or any dare maintain, that the Covenant of Grace giveth no conditional Right to any Infant in the VVorld? Are they all exclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded? And why? Are they worſe than their
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:170924:12"/>Parents? If it give any Right to Infants conditionally, as it doth to Parents, muſt it not be on a condition to be performed by the Parents, or ſuch as are ſo far entruſted?</p>
            <p>Or can this be called a Covenant,<note place="margin">V. p. 10<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</note> for God only to ſay [I will ſave all ſuch Infants as I elect] and yet offer Salvation to none of them in the World on any condition, nor give a title to any perſon that can be known by themſelves or others? Would it not be to confound the Decree of God with his Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venant? And what Right or hope doth this give to <hi>Chriſtians</hi> for their children, more than to <hi>Pagans?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Whether they that will lay all the Right of Infants to the pardon of ſin,<note place="margin">V. p. 209, 205.</note> and ſalvati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on upon ſecret election only; as if all that we knew of Infants ſalvation were, that God would ſave ſome whom he hath ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted: but that there is no promiſe of Grace or Salvation to any particular Infant in the World, as under any condition, or qualifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation? Whether they muſt not ſay, that no Infant hath any Right to Pardon, Grace and Salvation, given him by the Covenant of Grace; no more than any elect perſon at age hath before Faith and Regeneration? And muſt they not ſay too, that we have no aſſurance that God will ſave ten or three In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants in all the World? For he hath not told us whether he hath elected ſo many? Or that they may all, or almoſt all be ſaved, while the number of the Elect is unreveal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed? Or can they ſay, that any more of the
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:170924:13"/>children of the faithful are ſaved, than of the <hi>Heathens</hi> or <hi>Infidels;</hi> of thoſe that love God and keep his Commandment, than of thoſe that hate him? Yea, how can they have any proper hope upon Covenant-right, that God will ſave any one Individual In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fant in the World? For how can we hope (in this proper ſence) of any thing but what we do believe? And how can we believe what is not promiſed, or revealed? And ſo muſt not Parents thus far be left hopeleſs?</p>
            <p>And if God will ſave more (yea,<note place="margin">V. p. 205, 206.</note> ſo great numbers as we hope are ſaved in Infancy) than ever he promiſed to ſave, and gave any Antecedent Right to Salvation to, whether will it not open ſuch a gap to the hopes of preſumptuous <hi>Heathens</hi> and <hi>Infidels</hi> this way, as will croſs our common Doctrine? As ſome will ſay, why may he not do ſo alſo by Parents, at leaſt renewing them <hi>in tranſitu?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And further,<note place="margin">V. p. 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>2.</note> if God hath given no con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition or character Antecedent, as a differen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cing qualification of thoſe that he will ſave from thoſe that he will not, but only told us that he will ſave whom he liſteth, whether this maketh not Infants to be no Subjects of his Kingdom, under no Law, and ſo liable to no Judgment, nor to ſtand in judgment with the reſt of the World, but only to be uſed as Beaſts or Stones, by Divine natural motion as he will? And then if there be no Law that giveth Right to pardon and ſal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation to any one Infant in the World, and yet many are ſaved, will it not follow, that
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:170924:13"/>God is (as the prophane ſay) better than his word, and will ſave many to whom he ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver gave right to it by promiſe?</p>
            <p>Q. XXXVIII. Though all that are ſaved,<note place="margin">V. p. 203, 204.</note> are ſaved for the meritorious righteouſneſs of Chriſt, by way of free gift; yet whether the condition be not a ſutable acceptance? And why may not a Parent accept a Dona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion for his child, who hath no will to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept it for himſelf? Shall he be certainly ſhut out unto damnation? Or ſhall he have that gift abſolutely which is conditional to all others? Or is he not concerned in the Donation at all? And have not Infants guilt and miſery from their Parents? And though life and pardon be by Chriſt only, yet is it not congruous, that the meer con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition of acceptance may be performed by the Parents (while they cannot accept for themſelves?)</p>
            <p>Q. XXXIX.<note place="margin">V. p. 106, 107.</note> (Whether it be no advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage for children to be under an early en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gagement to God, and Jeſus Chriſt?) Whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther to dedicate them betimes to God, doth not tend to ſecure God's right and child<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rens good, and to prevent their ſin and mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſery; they being thus under a double Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligation, which they may be minded of be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times, and which may hold them more ſtrongly to their duty, and diſadvantage the Tempter that would draw them off from God?</p>
            <p>And may it not do much to awe the minds of children; yea,<note place="margin">V. p. 107.</note> and cauſe them to
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:170924:14"/>love that Chriſt which hath received them, and that Society to which they belong? And, is Infant-covenanting any hinderance in Nature, or Reaſon from perſonal ſerious covenanting with God at age? Do we not tell our children and all the adult, that their Infant-covenanting by Parents, will ſerve them but till they have Reaſon and will of their own to chuſe for themſelves?</p>
            <p>If it were deferred till ripeneſs of age would not one part neglect it and continue <hi>Infidels;</hi>
               <note place="margin">V. p. 222, 223.</note> and another part do all formally, as we ſee they do now at the other Sacra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, where the ſame Covenant is to be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>newed? Is there not a better remedy, that all that are baptized in Infancy ſhould as un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtandingly, and as ſeriouſly, and (if it may be conveniently) as ſolemnly, own and make that Covenant with God when they come to age, as if they had never been baptized (if not more, as being more obliged?)</p>
            <p>Is it not much liker to tend to the good of Souls,<note place="margin">V. p. 109.</note> and the propagating <hi>Chriſtianity,</hi> and the ſtrength of the Church for to have both the obligation and comfort of our In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fant-covenant, and Church-ſtate, and as ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious a covenanting alſo at age, when we paſs into the Church-ſtate of the Adult; than to be without the former, and left on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to the expectation of the latter?</p>
            <p>Whether to be ſeriouſly devoted to God by our Parents firſt,<note place="margin">V. p. 223.</note> and to be brought at age as ſeriouſly to devote our ſelves to him, as any Anabaptiſt can do, be not a much
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:170924:14"/>likelier way to fill the Church with ſerious <hi>Chriſtians,</hi> than to leave all men without an early Infant-obligation?</p>
            <p>Q. XL.<note place="margin">V. p. 156, 157.</note> Whether it can be proved that ever there was one Age, or Church (parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular) on Earth ſince <hi>Adam</hi> till about 200. years ago, that the Anabaptiſts roſe, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in Infants were not <hi>de facto</hi> taken for Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of the Church?</p>
            <p>Q. XLI. Whether it can be proved,<note place="margin">V. p. 157, 104.</note> that ever there was any one Infant of true Church-members, that was not rightfully a Church-member himſelf from the Creation till Chriſt's dayes? Or from the Creation till this day; except the Anabaptiſts, who reject the benefit, whoſe caſe we will not preſume to determine?</p>
            <p>Q. XLII.<note place="margin">V. p. 157, 158.</note> Seeing that Infants have been <hi>de facto,</hi> Church-members from the Creati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to this day (as far as any Records can lead us) Is it likely that the Lord, and Head and all ſufficient Governour of his Church, would have permitted his Church till now to be actually made up of ſuch Subjects, as in regard of age be diſallowed, and ſuffered his Church to be wrong framed till now? Or is it a reaſonable, modeſt, and lawful un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dertaking, to go about now in the end of the World to make God a new framed Church, as to the age of the Subjects? And is it not more modeſt and ſafe to live quietly in a Church of that frame, as all the Saints of Heaven lived in, till the other day, as a few Anabaptiſts did attempt an Alteration?</p>
            <pb n="22" facs="tcp:170924:15"/>
            <p> Q. XLIII.<note place="margin">V. p. 160.</note> Whether conſidering Chriſt's own Infant-memberſhip, and his kind re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ception of Infants, and his chiding thoſe that would have kept them off, and his of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fers of taking in all the <hi>Jewiſh</hi> Nation, (<hi>Matth.</hi> 23.37.) and that they were broken off by unbelief,<note place="margin">V. p. 143.</note> and conſequently the Seed of Believers not broken off from the Church Univerſal, and that whole Houſholds are oft ſaid to be baptized, and that <hi>Paul</hi> pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nounceth Believers children holy, and that Chriſt expreſly (<hi>Matth.</hi> 28.) commandeth his Miniſters, as much as in them lieth to diſciple all Nations baptizing them, and that it is propheſied that the Kingdoms of the World ſhall be made the Kingdoms of Chriſt, and there is no Nation or Kingdom on Earth that Infants are not Members of; whether in all this, and much more, there be not a plain notification of God's will, that as he never had a Church which excluded Infants; ſo neither doth he now exclude them?</p>
            <p>And if any will take him for Antichriſt that taketh Infants into the viſible Church,<note place="margin">V. p. 305.</note> whether it will not prove to be Chriſt him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf?</p>
            <p>Q. XLIV.<note place="margin">V. p. 209,</note> In ſumm, whether 1. God would not have Parents devote their children to him, and enter them according to their ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacity in his Covenant? 2. Whether alſo he doth not accept into his Covenant all that are faithfully thus devoted to him, and be not peculiarly their God, that ſuch children
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:170924:15"/>are holy? 3. Whether they are not as cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly Members, according to an Infant ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacity, of the viſible Church, as they are of all Kingdoms under Heaven? 4. Whether there be not far more hope of their Salvati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, than of thoſe without? 5. Whether the Covenant doth not make their Salvati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on certain, if they ſo die? 6. Whether the Inveſtiture and Solemnization of their Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venant with Chriſt ſhould not be made in Infancy?</p>
            <p>Whether ever it can be proved,<note place="margin">V. p. 233.</note> that granting Infants viſible Church-member<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, yet they are not to be baptized, and that Baptiſm was appointed for initiating none but adult Members? Whether Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſm be not the common entrance into the Church, and the plain Law of Chriſt, <hi>Matth.</hi> 28.19. and the Expoſition of the Univerſal Church doth not ſtand on Record to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fute ſuch an Opinion?</p>
            <p>Q. XLV.<note place="margin">Preface p. 4.</note> How inconſiderable a part of the Univerſal Church do the Anabaptiſts hold Communion with? And do they not unchurch almoſt all the Churches on Earth? (may we not think, that they rob Chriſt of more than nine parts of ten of his Kingdom, or Church Univerſal? <hi>V. p.</hi> 305.)</p>
            <p>Q. XLVI.<note place="margin">Preface ib.</note> Whether they can poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly hope that ever the Church on Earth will unite upon their terms, of reje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cting all their Infants from the viſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Church, and renouncing all our
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:170924:16"/>Infant Rights and Benefits conferred by the Baptiſmal Covenant of Grace?</p>
            <p>Q. XLVII.<note place="margin">Preface ib.</note> And whether if they conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue to the World's end to ſeparate from al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt all the Churches and unchurch them, their employment will not be ſtill to ſerve the great Enemy of Love and Concord, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Lord of Love and Peace, and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Proſperity of Faith and Godli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and againſt the welfare of the Church and Souls, and to the ſcandal and hardning of the ungodly?</p>
            <p>Q. XLVIII.<note place="margin">V. p. 189.</note> Whether too many well-meaning, but weak <hi>Chriſtians</hi> are not diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>affected to lawful and warrantable things in the Worſhip of God, meerly becauſe they ſee ſuch as are ungodly uſe and own them? And whether if God ſhould but let us have a King and other Rulers that were againſt Infant-baptiſm, and ſinging of Pſalms, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and would make Laws for their own way, and impoſe it on others, ſo that the ungod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly multitude ſhould fall in with them, it would not preſently cure many that are now for ſuch Opinions?</p>
            <p>Q. XLIX. Whether Mr. <hi>Baxter</hi> in the ſecond and third part of that his ſecond Defence of our Infants Rights, have not ſufficiently detected the great and notorious Untruths in Fact and Hiſtory, wherewith Mr. <hi>H. D.</hi> Treatiſe of Baptiſm, and Reply to Mr. <hi>Willes</hi> is fully ſtuffed?</p>
            <p>Q. L.<note place="margin">V. p. 228, 229.</note> Whether the Anabaptiſts Schiſm, or Separation from Communion with our
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:170924:16"/>Churches be not worſe (yet) than their ſimple O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pinion? And whether it be not deſirable, and poſſible, that ſome way be found out, and terms layd down in which good and ſober men on both ſides would agree and hold Communion? As <hi>v. g.</hi> If the Anabaptiſts would conſent to, and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſs as followeth, or to this ſence: <q>Though we judge Infant-baptiſm dſſonant from Chriſt's inſtituted Order, yet finding that God hath made many Promiſes to the Seed of the Faithful above others, and that Chriſt expreſſed his rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dineſs to receive little Children when they were brought to him for his Bleſſing, and knowing that all Chriſtian Parents ſhould earneſtly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire that their Children may be the Children of God through Chriſt, and ſhould devote them to him, as far as is in their power, and knowing that there are difficulties about the extent of this Power, and Chriſt's Promiſes; we do here ſolemnly profeſs, that we thankfully deſire all thoſe Mercies for this Child which God hath promiſed to ſuch in his Word; and that we heartily offer, devote and dedicate this Child to God the Father, Son, and Holy Ghoſt, as far as he hath given us power to do it, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeeching him accordingly to accept him: And we promiſe faithfully to endeavour to educate him in the nurture and admonition of the Lord, and as we are able to perſwade him when he is capable, to believe in Chriſt, and ſolemnly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vote himſelf to God the Father, Son, and Holy Ghoſt in Baptiſm.</q> If thus much were done in the Church, or ſo openly as may ſatisfie the Church, that they are not deſpiſers of God's mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies, nor of their Childrens Souls: And much more, if thoſe that profeſs that they cannot ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie their Conſciences in their Infant-baptiſm,<note place="margin">V. p. 230. 231.</note> would but do as the Liturgy doth by thoſe whoſe Baptiſm is uncertain, <hi>[If thou be not baptized, I
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:170924:17"/>baptize thee,]</hi> and ſo would ſay, [Being uncertain whether my Infant-baptiſm be valid, if it be not I now receive that which is.] And when they have ſatisfied their Conſciences, would live quiet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in the Love and Communion of the Church, who would not receive them, though we approve not of their way?</p>
            <p>And ſhould not we be willing to give ſatisfacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on by ſuch an anſwerable profeſſion as this? <q>Though it be our Judgment that Infants have ever been Members of God's viſible Church, ſince he had a Church and there were Infants in the World, and do believe that Chriſt hath ſignified in the Goſpel that it is his gracious will, that they ſhould ſtill be ſo, and that he hath made Baptiſm the regular orderly way of ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lemn entrance into a viſible Church-ſtate; and therefore we devote this Child to God in the Baptiſmal Covenant: yet we do alſo hold, that when he cometh to age, it will be his duty as ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riouſly and devoutly to make this Covenant with God underſtandingly himſelf, and to dedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate himſelf to God the Father, Son, and Holy Ghoſt, as thoſe muſt do that never were bapti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zed in Infancy: And we promiſe to endeavour faithfully as we have opportunity, to inſtruct and perſwade him ſo to do, hoping that this his early Baptiſmal Dedication and Obligation to God, will rather much prepare him for it, than hinder it.</q>
            </p>
            <p>Whether might not ſome ſuch Profeſſions put off the chief matter of Offence and Exception a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt each other, as to the ill conſequents of our Opinions? and would not ſober good men by ſuch a mutual approach, be more diſpoſed to live together in Love and Holy Peace (which we ſhould all pray for, and what in us lieth, as far as poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly we can, promote?)</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
